<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<Root><h1>Equipment</h1>
<p>The weapons, armor, and tools your characters bring on their mission can have a huge impact on how successful you are: a more robust piece of armor could turn a blade that would mean 
death; a silencer attached to a laspistol might mean you aren't discovered, and pair of magnocs could help you witness a key event in your investigation.</p>

<h2>Old Equipment Tags</h2>
<p>All weapon tags from vanilla Dungeon World are still in use for Heresy World.</p>

<h2>New Equipment Tags</h2>
<ul><li><em>Long</em>: Ranged only. It is useful for attacking something beyond shouting distance. When attempting a shot at Long distance you take -1 on your roll.</li>
<li><em>n Uses</em>: Items with <em>n</em> Uses can be used <em>n</em> times before you must take a moment to reload.</li>
<li><em>Scatter</em>: Ranged only. Roll two damage die when at <em>close</em> range.</li>
<li><em>Tearing</em>: When dealing damage with this weapon roll an extra damage die and discard the lowest.</li>
<li><em>n Rending</em>: This weapons tears and destroys the target's defenses. The target's armor is reduced by <em>n</em> when they take wounds from this weapon.</li>
<li><em>Silenced</em>: The sound of this weapon firing is greatly reduced.</li>
<li><em>Razor-sharp</em>: When rolling any move that deals damage, this weapon ignores armor on a 10+.</li>
<li><em>n Proven</em>: This weapon always strikes true. When rolling for damage with this weapon, treat any roll below <em>n</em> as having rolled <em>n</em>.</li>
<li><em>Power</em>: Melee only. This item has a power field that can be activated. While active, you take the better of two rolls for damage and this item gains <tag k="messy"></tag>.</li>
<li><em>Rare</em>: This item is rare and hard to locate. You might find one in a large city if you know where to look.</li>
<li><em>Very Rare</em>: This item is exceedingly hard to find. You might find one like it if you scour the galaxy.</li></ul>
</Root>