<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no" ?>
<Root><h1>What is Heresy World?</h1>
<p>Heresy World is a pen and paper role playing game expansion for Dungeon World, where players act as Acolytes of an Inquisitor in the universe of Warhammer 40,000.</p>

<h2>What do I need to know before playing?</h2>
<p>Heresy World assumes you already are familiar with both the Dungeon World game and the Warhammer 40,000 universe, specifically the Inquisition.</p>

<h1>How is Heresy World different from Dungeon World?</h1>
<h2>The Setting</h2>
<p>Heresy World takes place in the grim dark future of the 41st millenium. This game assumes you are familiar with the Warhammer 40,000 universe by Games Workshop. The forces of mankind live on million of planets under the rule of the Imperium of Man, a galaxy spanning empire created during the Great Crusade by the God-Emperor of man - may he ever sit the Golden Throne - and shaped since then by the events of the Horus Heresy and the 10,000 years of war against xenos, mutants, rebels, and Chaos that followed. It is a dark time, where death and pain are constants, and the only salvation is undying loyalty to the Emperor.</p>

<h2>The Mission</h2>
<p>Unlike Dungeon World where characters are free to set out to pursue whichever adventure piques their interest, players in Heresy World take on a role with a given purpose. In Heresy World you play as an Acolyte of an Inquisitor, an agent of the Holy Orders of the Emperor's Inquisition, more commonly known as the Inquisition. Your Inquisitor will send you on various missions to discover heresy, and root out corruption in the Imperium. Your task is to keep the empire safe from enemies that lie within its borders.</p>
<p>Because characters in Heresy World start with a position and job, it is assumed that their lifestyle is much less open-ended than a character in Dungeon World. Of course you shouldn't necessarily let this force you not to play the game how you want, but keep in mind the motivations of your characters and the implications that would come from abondoning your missions for your own pursuits.</p>

<h2>The Gameplay</h2> 
<p>The core gameplay mechanics of Heresy World is very similar to Dungeon World. A few key things have changed, and many minor ones. Some of the bigger changes are:</p>
<ul><li>New Basic Moves and Special Moves have been added</li>
<li>Three new classes are available: Assassin, Investigator, Warrior</li>
<li>A master list of Advanced Moves is available for all classes to take</li>
<li>Character creation also involves choosing a Background and a Home World for your character</li>
<li>Volley is mostly replaced by Fire for Effect</li>
<li>All ranged weapons need to be reloaded</li>
<li>Discern Realities uses a hold mechanic for answering questions</li>
<li>Discern Realities has a different list of questions</li>
<li>End of Session has different questions to ask the group</li>
<li>Last Breath no longer offers deals with Death</li>
<li>Fronts have been bolstered by Missions</li>
<li>Many pieces of equipment have been renamed to fit the new setting</li>
<li>New equipment tags and types of gear have been added</li>
<li>Ancient artefact examples are available</li>
<li>The GM's Agenda has been changed slightly to fit the grim dark setting</li>
<li>New moves are available to the GM to mutate, terrify, and traumatize the characters</li></ul></Root>